<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microeconomic Analysis</title>
    <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Microeconomic Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1. The Tools of Microeconomics</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.1-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.1-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Preliminary Survey   Overview An introduction to the course and the tools we use in microeconomics.
Slides   Lecture Slides  Preliminary Survey Please take the preliminary survey on your math background. This will help us all have a productive course together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 Optimization and the Budget Constraint - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.3-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.3-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Practice Problems Math Survey Math Review   Thursday, January 23, 2020
Overview We begin with an overview of constrained optimization models and our first application, how individuals choose. Our primary focus will be people as consumers - how do they choose to spend their money and how do those choices change? While we will focus extensively on consumers making purchasing choices, do not think this is the only use of this type of model!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 Optimization and the Budget Constraint - Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.3-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.3-practice/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF  Answer Key  You can get music via downloads (\(d\)) or concert tickets (\(t\)). You have $60 to spend each week, and the price of a download is $3 and the price of a concert ticket is $10. Put \(d\) on the horizontal axis and \(t\) on the vertical axis.
1 Write the equation for your budget constraint.
 2 Solve this equation for \(t\), to express the equation of the line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 Optimization and the Budget Constraint - Readings</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.3-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.3-reading/</guid>
      <description>Recommended   Ch. 4.3 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  Now that we are picking up the intensity and working with some models (many will be new to you at first), I recommend looking at the textbook readings for each class.
We are going a bit out of order in two ways. First, Goolsbee et. al start with a review of Supply and Demand in chapters 2-3, and don’t get to “Consumer Theory” (what we are starting now) until chapter 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.4 Preferences I: Indifference Curves - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.4-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.4-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Practice Problems Math Appendix Utility Functions and PMTs    Tuesday, January 28, 2020
Overview We continue with our model of how individuals choose. Our focus for this class, and next, is what are people’s objectives? How can we operationalize their preferences in a meaningful way? Today we will discuss one tool - indifference curves - and start an explanation of utility and how we can model people as trying to “maximize” it (we will wrap that up in the next class).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.4 Preferences I: Indifference Curves - Readings</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.4-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.4-reading/</guid>
      <description> Recommended   Ch. 4.1-4.2 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5 Preferences II: Indifference Curves - MRS and Utility Functions</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.5-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.5-reading/</guid>
      <description>Recommended   Ch. 4.1-4.2 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  This is the same reading as last class (we are taking two class periods to cover preferences).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5 Preferences II: Indifference Curves - MRS and Utility Functions</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.6-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.6-reading/</guid>
      <description> Recommended   Ch. 4.4-4.5 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5 Preferences II: MRS and Marginal Utility - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.5-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.5-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Practice Problems Math Appendix Graphing Indifference Curves Utility Functions for Perfect Substitutes Utility Functions for Perfect Complements Cobb-Douglas Functions    Thursday, January 30, 2020
Overview We continue with our model of how individuals choose. Our focus for this class is to wrap up what we mean by “maximizing utility” as a person’s objective. We will do some practice problems on understanding indifference curves and utility functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.5 Preferences II: MRS and Utility Functions - Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.5-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.5-practice/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF  Answer Key  1 For each question, draw an indifference curve relating the two objects (label it \(I_1\)). Draw and label a second curve that gives higher utility (label it \(I_2\)), and a third curve that gives lower utility (label it \(I_0\)).
a. Oranges (a good) on the horizontal axis and Pollution (a bad) on the vertical axis.
 b. Pollution (a bad) on the horizontal axis and Soda (a good) on the vertical axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.6 Solving the Consumer&#39;s Problem - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.6-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.6-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Practice Problems Assignment: Problem Set 1 Math Appendix Solving the Constrained Optimization Problem with Calculus    Thursday, February 6, 2020
Overview Today we put all of our tools together thus far to solve the consumer’s constrained optimization problem. To solve the problem the “traditional way” would be to use Lagrangian multipliers and calculus and solve for the first order conditions. We instead will find the solution by looking graphically, and use an algebraic rule that should make intuitive sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.6 Solving the Consumer&#39;s Problem - Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.6-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.6-practice/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF  Answer Key  You can get utility from consuming Soda \((s)\) and Hot dogs \((h)\), according to the utility function:
\[u(s,h)=\sqrt{sh}\]
The marginal utilities are:
\[\begin{align*} MU_s&amp;amp;=0.5s^{-0.5}h^{0.5} \\ MU_h&amp;amp;=0.5s^{0.5}h^{-0.5} \\ \end{align*}\]
You have an income of $12, the price of Soda is $2, and the price of a Hot dog is $3. Put Soda on the horizontal axis and Hot dogs on the vertical axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7 Building a Demand Function - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.7-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.7-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Practice Problems Assignments: Problem Sets 1, 2, and Exam 1   Tuesday, February 11, 2020
Overview Solving a single constrained optimum problem might be useful in certain contexts, but the dynamics of change are more interesting: how do people optimally respond to changes in constraints? The remaining few classes before Exam 1 are about how people respond to changes in prices and income. If we can describe this set of behaviors in an equation and graphically, it is the origin of a demand curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7 Building a Demand Function - Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.7-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.7-practice/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF  Answer Key  You can spend your income on apples and oranges. Apples currently cost $0.25 and oranges cost $0.50. When your income is $40, you buy 10 apples and 8 oranges. When your income increases to $80, you buy 12 apples and 6 oranges.
1. What type of good are apples (inferior, necessity, luxury)?
 2. What type of good are oranges (inferior, necessity, or luxury)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7 Building a Demand Function - Readings</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.7-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.7-reading/</guid>
      <description> Recommended   Ch. 5.1, 5.2, 5.4 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.8 Income and Substitution Effects - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.8-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.8-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Interactive Examples Practice Problems Assignments: Problem Set 1 is DUE and Problem Set 2 Math Appendix Example Demand Functions Cobb-Douglas    Thursday, February 13, 2020
Overview Today we cover the third effect: the (own) price effect, aka the law of demand: how changes in a good’s (own) price affect quantity demanded for that good. We introduce the idea of demand functions, inverse demand functions, and a demand curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.8 Income and Substitution Effects - Readings</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.8-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.8-reading/</guid>
      <description> Recommended   Ch. 2.2, 5.3 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.9 Price Elasticity - Class Notes</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.9-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.9-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Overview Slides Example Applications of Consumer Theory Models Practice Problems Assignments: Problem Set 1 Answers, Problem Set 2 Due Next Class, Exam 1   Tuesday, February 18, 2020
Overview Today we look at price elasticity of demand, and wrap up our Unit 1 on Consumer/Individual choice theory.
A reminder, your second problem set is due next class; next class is our review session, and we will have Exam 1 on Tuesday October 1 (for Section 1 - TuTh) and Wednesday October 2 (for Section 2 - MW).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.9 Price Elasticity - Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.9-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/practice/1.9-practice/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF  Answer Key  The demand for monthly cell phone plans is given by:
\[q_D = 50-0.5p\]
1. Write the inverse demand function.
 2. Calculate the price elasticity of demand when the price is $10. Is this relatively elastic or inelastic?
 3. Calculate the price elasticity of demand when the price is $70. Is this relatively elastic or inelastic?
 4. At what price is demand unit elastic \((\epsilon=-1)\)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.9 Price Elasticity - Readings</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.9-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reading/1.9-reading/</guid>
      <description> Recommended   Ch. 2.2, 2.5, 5.5 in Austan Goolsbee, Steven Levitt, and Chad SyversonMicroeconomics, 2nd ed. (USA: Worth Publishers, 2012).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignments/</guid>
      <description>Grade Calculator   Grade Calculator  Use this tool to calculate your final course grade and predict what grades you would need on remaining assignments to obtain a desired course grade.
Homeworks There will be roughly a homework assignment for every lesson. These questions will help check your understanding and mastery of the material, and will be a combination of quantitative, graph, and short answer questions of examples. These will also be good indicators of what to expect on the exams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2: Scarcity, Choice, and Cost</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.2-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/class/1.2-class/</guid>
      <description> Contents  Overview Slides Survey   Overview Before we jump into our optimization models to descibe and predict (changes in) individual choices and behavior, we cover the basic principles of choice and action in a world of scarcity. This is what motivates economics.
Slides   Lecture Slides  Survey </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 1 Information</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-exam/</guid>
      <description>Exam 1 is Tuesday, February 25, 2020
If you have any approved testing accomodations, or know you will be absent for the exam, please let me know ASAP.
Concepts Study Guide   Download PDF  “Practice” Exam   Download Old Exam 1  Above, you have a previous semester’s actual exam. Use it to get a sense of what questions are asked, the format, and how many. Questions draw from topics in Unit 1, and note that just because topics or questions were not in the practice exam does NOT mean they may not show up on your exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinion-Editorial Assignment</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/op-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/op-ed/</guid>
      <description>Due by the last day of class
   How to Write a Good Paper See examples of good student Op-eds on Blackboard (Course Documents)   “How can I know what I think until I see what I say?” — E. M. Forster on Writing
 Overview Your task is to write an Opinion-Editorial (Op-ed) piece that applies the economic way of thinking to some public policy-relevant issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Survey on Math Background</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/preliminary-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/preliminary-survey/</guid>
      <description>Due by Tuesday, January 21, 2019
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  This is an ungraded and anonymous survey for me to evaluate the distribution of your math and statistics backgrounds. Please write your answers the the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You do not need to write your name on it. Please complete all problems to the best of your ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 1</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by Thursday, February 13, 2020
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  Please write your answers to the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You may also type your answers and print out a hard copy.
You may work together (and I highly encourage that) but you must turn in your own answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 2</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by Thursday, February 20, 2020
  Download as PDF  Please write your answers to the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You may also type your answers and print out a hard copy.
You may work together (and I highly encourage that) but you must turn in your own answers. Your TA, under my supervision, will grade homeworks 70% for completion, and for the remaining 30%, pick one question to grade for accuracy - so it is best that you try every problem, even if you are unsure how to complete it accurately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/reference/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Tips for Success Math Review List of Math Appendices Interactive Examples   Look here over the course of the semester for resources, links, and tips on how to succeed in the course, how to write well, and other things of interest related to microeconomics.
Tips for Success Take notes. On paper. Yes. Studies show that using pen and paper trump taking notes on a device. The main reason is because you cannot possibly write down everything I am saying by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/schedule/</guid>
      <description>This page contains all of the following resources for each class meeting:
  Readings include textbook chapters and occasional journal articles  Assignments are due by the beginning of class unless otherwise stated  Class materials contain extra explanations, math/statistical properties &amp;amp; proofs, and other helpful resourcesThese “online appendices” keep the slides nice and de-cluttered!
  Slides are “Xaringan” presentations in html that can be opened in any browserFile &amp;gt; Print &amp;gt; Save as PDF if you wish to download them</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Download as PDF
 Last Updated: January 20, 2019
   “The curious task of economics is to demonstrate to men how little they really know about what they imagine they can design.” - F.A. Hayek, 1974 Economics Nobel Laureate
 Microeconomic Analysis&amp;#8853;Instructor
Dr. Ryan Safner
 118 Rosenstock
safner@hood.edu
@ryansafner
 Office hours: MW 3:30–5:00PM
Course
 TuTh
 January 15–May 8, 2020
 11:30 AM–12:45 PM</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>