<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on Microeconomic Analysis</title>
    <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on Microeconomic Analysis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 1 Information</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-exam/</guid>
      <description>Exam 1 is Tuesday, February 25, 2020
If you have any approved testing accomodations, or know you will be absent for the exam, please let me know ASAP.
Concepts Study Guide   Download PDF  “Practice” Exam   Download Old Exam 1  Old Exam 1 Answer Key  Above, you have a previous semester’s actual exam. Use it to get a sense of what questions are asked, the format, and how many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam 2 Information</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-exam/</guid>
      <description>Exam 2 will be available 8:00 AM Tuesday, April 7 through 10:00 PM Sunday April 12 on BlackboardGo to our class Blackboard page, on the blue navigation bar on the left, click Assignments, you will find Exam 2.

Exam Instructions (IMPORTANT, PLEASE READ) This test will be available on Blackboard as a timed assignment. You will have 2 hours once you open the test on Blackboard. You will not need the whole time, I have given you some extra to accomodate the difficulties of taking an exam at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinion-Editorial Assignment</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/op-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/op-ed/</guid>
      <description>Due by the last day of class
   How to Write a Good Paper See examples of good student Op-eds on Blackboard (Course Documents)   “How can I know what I think until I see what I say?” — E. M. Forster on Writing
 Overview Your task is to write an Opinion-Editorial (Op-ed) piece that applies the economic way of thinking to some public policy-relevant issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Survey on Math Background</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/preliminary-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/preliminary-survey/</guid>
      <description>Due by Tuesday, January 21, 2019
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  This is an ungraded and anonymous survey for me to evaluate the distribution of your math and statistics backgrounds. Please write your answers the the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You do not need to write your name on it. Please complete all problems to the best of your ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 1</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/01-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by Thursday, February 13, 2020
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  Please write your answers to the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You may also type your answers and print out a hard copy.
You may work together (and I highly encourage that) but you must turn in your own answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 2</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/02-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by Thursday, February 20, 2020
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  Please write your answers to the following questions on a piece of paper, or download and print a PDF copy (link above) to write on. You may also type your answers and print out a hard copy.
You may work together (and I highly encourage that) but you must turn in your own answers. Your TA, under my supervision, will grade homeworks 70% for completion, and for the remaining 30%, pick one question to grade for accuracy - so it is best that you try every problem, even if you are unsure how to complete it accurately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 3</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/03-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/03-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by 11:59 PM Sunday, March 29, 2020 by email
  Download as PDF  Answer Key  Updated Instructions for Online Course (Please Read!) Please type your answers to the following questions in a document and email it (as MS Word, PDF, etc) to me. You may still handwrite answers if you will be able to scan and email them if they are easily readable, but this is not preferred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 4</title>
      <link>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/04-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microS20.classes.ryansafner.com/assignment/04-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>Due by 11:59 PM Sunday, April 5, 2020 by email
  Download as PDF  Updated Instructions for Online Course (Please Read!) Please type your answers to the following questions in a document and email a PDF attachment to me.In MS Word, or Pages, or most word processing software, File -&amp;gt; Save As -&amp;gt; PDF, or File -&amp;gt; Export -&amp;gt; PDF.
 You may still handwrite answers if you will be able to scan and email them, as a PDF, if they are easily readable, but this is not preferred.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>